<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[A starter blog demonstrating what Gatsby can do.]]></description><link>https://quantably.co</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 10:12:54 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[About]]></title><description><![CDATA[My Journey in AI and Data Science With 15 years in the technology sector and over a decade focused on data science and AI, I've built…]]></description><link>https://quantably.co/about/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://quantably.co/about/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;My Journey in AI and Data Science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 15 years in the technology sector and over a decade focused on data science and AI, I&apos;ve built practical solutions across industries that deliver measurable business impact. My journey from mathematician to AI team leader has taught me many lessons about what makes AI implementations succeed—and why they often fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lessons That Shape My Approach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Focus on the Right Data, Not Just More Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At IBM, I discovered that carefully selected data often outperforms massive datasets for classical ML models. This principle of quality over quantity continues to guide my approach today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Start Simple, Measure Everything&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Elsevier, working on recommender systems taught me the power of simplicity. I learned that basic models often outperform complex ones, and that connecting internal metrics to business outcomes like customer satisfaction and retention is essential for success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bridge Research and Product&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coolest technology means nothing if it doesn&apos;t become part of a product that delivers value. I&apos;ve learned to collaborate closely with product teams to ensure technical innovations translate into customer benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Respect the Data Foundation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Experian, building transaction classification models reinforced how critical proper data annotation and understanding is to successful AI implementation. Before advanced models, you need solid data foundations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Adapt to Constraints&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with Quin, a med-tech startup, taught me to adapt ML approaches to device limitations and strict regulatory requirements—valuable experience for any company implementing AI in constrained environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lead with Purpose&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Monolith AI, I&apos;ve led teams of 4 to 20 people across forward-deployed data science, machine learning engineering, and research functions. This experience has refined my leadership approach: small, focused teams driven by clear metrics and business outcomes consistently outperform larger, less directed efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My approach is straightforward: understand your data, build simple solutions first, measure what matters to your business, and focus relentlessly on customer outcomes. This methodology consistently delivers AI solutions that work in the real world—not just in the lab.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Media]]></title><description><![CDATA[Title Description Link AI Career Spotlight An interview with Catherine Breslin where I discuss my journey into AI, leadership, meta-skills…]]></description><link>https://quantably.co/media/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://quantably.co/media/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;AI Career Spotlight&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;An interview with Catherine Breslin where I discuss my journey into AI, leadership, meta-skills and more&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/ai-career-spotlight-peter-wooldridge-catherine-breslin-hfzje/?trackingId=ZbMXcWTRSButGuiWfRKIHw%3D%3D&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Link →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Home]]></title><link>https://quantably.co/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://quantably.co/</guid><content:encoded></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Projects]]></title><description><![CDATA[GlucoseInsights GlucoseInsights is an iOS mobile app I developed to help those (like myself) manage their Type 1 Diabetes in and around…]]></description><link>https://quantably.co/projects/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://quantably.co/projects/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;GlucoseInsights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.glucoseinsights.com/&quot;&gt;GlucoseInsights&lt;/a&gt; is an iOS mobile app I developed to help those (like myself) manage their Type 1 Diabetes in and around exercise. It combines workout data, continuous glucose monitoring (CGM) data alongside other metrics to help understand patterns in their data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;StravaTalk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pwxn/StravaTalk&quot;&gt;StravaTalk&lt;/a&gt; is a conversational interface for Strava data that lets you analyse your activities using natural language. Built with the Atomic Agents framework, it transforms simple English questions into database queries and returns human-friendly responses.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Your Company is One Resignation Away from AI Disaster]]></title><description><![CDATA[Imagine halving your programme development time with AI only to realise the entire operation hinges on a single motivated employee who could walk out the door tomorrow.]]></description><link>https://quantably.co/ai-paradox/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://quantably.co/ai-paradox/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Imagine halving your programme development time with AI only to realise the entire operation hinges on a single motivated employee who could walk out the door tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One corporate training company I spoke to recently faced exactly this dilemma. Their impressive AI success created an unexpected vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their AI-secret wasn&apos;t a complex strategy, but a single curious employee who, through trial and error, figured out how to combine LLMs with their deep industry knowledge building well-crafted prompts and applying them throughout their business. AI was used to streamline everything from client discovery, content creation through to quality assurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds great, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these efficiencies hide a big vulnerability: that their business is one resignation away from AI disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&apos;t just hypothetical. The problem became clear during one of the team&apos;s post-training analysis calls. The AI expert would usually generate detailed analysis reports right after a training session - giving clients immediate, actionable feedback to discuss during the call. When their AI specialist was unexpectedly absent, there was no one able to step in and generate the reports. The team didn&apos;t understand how to use the tools, leaving them floundering on the call risking reputation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This scenario highlights an emerging risk that many businesses adopting AI face. The tool that gives companies a competitive edge can also represent their biggest vulnerability. While everyone rushes to implement AI faster, sustainable implementation is often overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Hidden Vulnerability in Your AI Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pattern repeats across industries. For smaller companies and non-tech organisations, where formal AI training programmes don&apos;t exist, success increasingly relies on what we might call &quot;AI pioneers&quot; - those who take initiative to explore and implement AI solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These pioneers, often through hours of persistence and experimentation, disrupt established workflows often for the better. The systems they build are often brilliant, but their knowledge remains largely undocumented and unshared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While AI success stories are celebrated across industries, the vulnerability they create remains largely undiscussed. Consider these increasingly common scenarios:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marketing teams with sophisticated prompt libraries but no documentation of techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operations departments with streamlined AI workflows known only to their creator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer service systems built on complex LLM knowledge that lives in a single person&apos;s head&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In each case, if the AI pioneer leaves, the team is left scrambling. The competitive edge built on their AI skills disappears overnight. This isn&apos;t just a people problem – it&apos;s a fundamental business risk tied directly to their AI adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Building an AI Knowledge Mesh&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a better way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI resilience requires distributing knowledge across the organisation. Rather than concentrating expertise in a few individuals, forward-thinking companies are creating knowledge networks that capture these learnings systematically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organisations who successfully distribute their AI knowledge and expertise, experience numerous benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Higher overall productivity and efficiency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased talent retention and knowledge preservation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greater resilience to disruption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced operational risks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This transformation shifts AI knowledge from a pyramid structure (with expertise concentrated in single individuals) into a mesh - where knowledge, including the valuable lessons from trial and error are shared, documented, and accessible to everyone who needs it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Transforming Vulnerability into Strength&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following represents a three-step process to transform this AI vulnerability into organisational strength:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Audit &amp;#x26; Document&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; Create a comprehensive map of your AI operations to understand where knowledge currently resides and capture the experimental journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify and map high-level workflows including current AI touchpoints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a company &quot;AI Playbook&quot; that includes a central library of effective prompts, documenting both successful approaches and failed experiments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record video walkthroughs of common AI tasks, including troubleshooting techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Share Knowledge &amp;#x26; Train&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; Transform siloed expertise into collective knowledge through structured learning and practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organise bi-weekly &quot;AI Skill Share&quot; sessions where pioneers demonstrate their processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish mentor-mentee pairs for hands-on learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rotate AI responsibilities among team members to build practical experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Implement &amp;#x26; Maintain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; Build resilience into your AI operations through redundancy and contingency planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure multiple team members are trained to run each critical AI process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop offline alternatives for critical workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish emergency response procedures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crucially, this isn&apos;t a one-time checklist but an ongoing cycle. Regularly revisit each phase to adapt to new tools, evolving processes, and changing team knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Building AI Resilience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having AI initiatives dependent on a few key people is a common challenge, but one you can overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I help businesses transform fragile AI dependency into robust, organisation-wide capability, addressing challenges such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify hidden risks:&lt;/strong&gt; Uncover exactly where your critical AI knowledge gaps and dependencies lie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Develop a clear roadmap:&lt;/strong&gt; Create a practical, tailored plan to distribute expertise and build shared understanding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement sustainable practices:&lt;/strong&gt; Embed proven strategies for documentation, training, and ongoing knowledge sharing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the above sounds like something you could benefit from, feel free to schedule a free call to discuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cal.com/quantably/30min&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; className=&quot;book-call-button&quot;&gt;Book a call here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember: Sustainable AI implementation is the key to long-term success.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Navigating the Shift from Deterministic to Probabilistic Software Engineering]]></title><description><![CDATA[Software engineering is at a crossroads. For decades, the craft has been built on deterministic foundations – where 2+2 always equals 4 and…]]></description><link>https://quantably.co/deterministic-to-probabilistic/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://quantably.co/deterministic-to-probabilistic/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Software engineering is at a crossroads. For decades, the craft has been built on deterministic foundations – where 2+2 always equals 4 and the same inputs reliably produce the same outputs. But as we advance into the era of AI agents, we&apos;re witnessing a fundamental shift toward probabilistic thinking that&apos;s changing what it means to be a software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Deterministic vs. Probabilistic Paradigm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional software engineering operates in a binary world: good or bad, pass or fail. When 100% of the tests pass, you can ship your product. It&apos;s clean, predictable, and comfortably black and white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probabilistic software, on the other hand, abandons these binary outcomes in favour of statistical efficacy. The questions shift from &quot;Will this work?&quot; to &quot;What&apos;s the likelihood of this working?&quot; This reframing is crucial as we build and deploy increasingly autonomous AI systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&apos;t entirely new territory – we&apos;ve had machine learning systems for years. But with the advent of the agentic movement, probabilistic thinking is becoming less of a specialised skill and more of a fundamental requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Complexity and Uncertainty&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As agents become more autonomous their non-deterministic aspects introduce new challenges:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increased variability in outputs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Difficulty in comprehensive testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complex security and consistency requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These complexities demand engineers to develop new mental models for designing, testing, and monitoring AI-based solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Reality Behind the Hype: Why Coding Skills Still Matter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube is filled with claims that you can &quot;lay off your entire team&quot; or &quot;become a 10x developer&quot; simply by combining tools like Cursor and some MCP servers. While these tools are powerful and impressive, there&apos;s still a substantial gap between flashy proof-of-concept and production-ready system. Not all generated code is correct or useful – you need discernment to evaluate it effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experienced software engineers understand that coding is just one part of the job. In reality, a substantial part of a senior engineer&apos;s role includes looking at systems holistically, anticipating potential failure points, analysing technical debt, aligning activities with product roadmaps, mentoring team members, and understanding how systems behave at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These skills become even more critical when dealing with complex, probabilistic AI systems. The value of software engineering isn&apos;t diminishing – what&apos;s changing is the additional skillset required to effectively leverage AI tools while still putting systems into production that manage the necessary trade-offs between latency, scale, and reliability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finding the Right Balance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first question when considering an agent should be: do I actually need one? Not everything requires a probabilistic approach. Sometimes deterministic software is perfectly sufficient – and an &quot;agent&quot; could still be running deterministic software under the hood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Adapting to the Agentic Age&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For engineers who have determined they need to build agent-based systems, several approaches can help navigate the non-deterministic behaviour:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embrace Structured Outputs&lt;/strong&gt; – The goal isn&apos;t to coerce these models to become deterministic – their probabilistic nature is precisely what makes them powerful. Instead, we need to leverage that strength while building reliable systems. Tools like the Instructor library can be a great starting point in creating controllable structured outputs from LLM models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Validating Systems&lt;/strong&gt; – Increasingly, we&apos;ll use AI systems to verify results from other AI components, creating internal validation loops. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/learn/cookbook/llm_judge&quot;&gt;LLM-as-a-judge&lt;/a&gt; for a practical example of using language models to evaluate other AI outputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn from Existing Systems that Operate Under Uncertainty&lt;/strong&gt; – We&apos;re not starting from zero. Reinforcement learning and many machine learning techniques already operate under probabilistic uncertainty. We can and should apply these lessons to agent-based systems. Google&apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-research2023-media/pubtools/4156.pdf&quot;&gt;ML Test Score&lt;/a&gt; provides a fantastic checklist to assess production-readiness of ML systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on the Right Problems and Metrics&lt;/strong&gt; – Understand the problem you&apos;re solving first, not just input/output results or benchmark scores. Ensure your data and metrics accurately represent real-world conditions. Rather than chasing corner cases, evaluate performance across diverse test distributions to build systems that solve the actual problem, not just optimise for artificial metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Hybrid Future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future isn&apos;t probabilistic versus deterministic – it&apos;s both. We&apos;ll need all the strengths of traditional software development alongside these new approaches to probabilistic systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complementary nature of these paradigms will produce the most powerful results as we build increasingly autonomous and capable systems. Great software engineers will be those who can navigate both worlds effectively, understanding when to apply each approach and how to combine them seamlessly.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building StravaTalk - A Natural Language Interface for Strava Data]]></title><description><![CDATA[In the rapidly evolving world of AI agents, finding the right framework can be challenging. After exploring numerous options that often…]]></description><link>https://quantably.co/conversational-strava/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://quantably.co/conversational-strava/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In the rapidly evolving world of AI agents, finding the right framework can be challenging. After exploring numerous options that often added complexity rather than solving problems, I discovered Atomic Agents - a lightweight, flexible framework that perfectly balances sophistication with simplicity. This weekend project lets me analyze years of Strava workout data through natural language questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a running enthusiast, I&apos;ve accumulated years of workout data in Strava. While the platform offers basic analytics, I wanted the ability to query this treasure trove of information using natural language - asking questions like &quot;What was my longest run last month?&quot; or &quot;Show me my average cycling speed this year&quot; without building complex filters or exports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend project is PoC to explore the capabilities of Atomic Agents, but it demonstrates the potential for more sophisticated applications in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enter StravaTalk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pwxn/StravaTalk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;StravaTalk&lt;/a&gt; is a conversational interface that lets me analyse my Strava activities using natural language. Built on the Atomic Agents framework, it transforms English questions into database queries and returns human-friendly responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/images/StravaTalk.gif&quot; alt=&quot;StravaTalk App&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How It Works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application follows a straightforward workflow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Preparation&lt;/strong&gt;: First, I used the Strava API to export my historical workout records to a local SQLite database. This one-time setup provides the foundation for all queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Query Processing&lt;/strong&gt;: When a user enters a natural language question, it flows through a pipeline of specialised AI agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application uses a multi-agent architecture with three specialised AI components built with Atomic Agents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Classification Agent&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gatekeeper determines if your query can be answered using available Strava data. It analyses the question, identifies what data would be required, and classifies it as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQL-appropriate (can be answered with available data)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not SQL-appropriate (requires data we don&apos;t have)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clarification needed (ambiguous query)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. SQL Agent&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For questions that can be answered, this agent converts natural language into optimised SQL queries. It understands the database schema (activities, segments, etc.) and builds queries that accurately represent the user&apos;s intent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Response Agent&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This agent transforms raw database results into human-friendly responses. It formats data with appropriate units (converting metres to kilometres, formatting pace correctly), and presents information in an engaging, motivational way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Shared Memory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most powerful features is the shared memory implementation. All agents access the same conversation context, enabling follow-up questions like &quot;How does that compare to last year?&quot; without repeating context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Structured Outputs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Atomic Agents&apos; integration with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jxnl/instructor&quot;&gt;Instructor&lt;/a&gt;, the entire system works with strongly typed outputs. This reduces hallucinations and ensures data consistency across the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Development Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What impressed me most about building with Atomic Agents was how quickly I could go from concept to working prototype. The framework strikes an excellent balance between:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Production-ready features (robust error handling, performance optimisation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developer experience (clean, readable code)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexibility (easy to customise and extend)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I completed the initial version in a single weekend, something that would have taken weeks with many other frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;StravaTalk demonstrates how modern AI frameworks can transform personal data into conversational insights. While this project focuses on Strava data, the architecture could be applied to any structured dataset. Thanks to frameworks like Atomic Agents, building sophisticated AI applications is becoming increasingly accessible to developers, opening up new possibilities for natural, conversation-driven interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>